Let me give you an example from
سأعطيك مثالًا من
my own experience of hiring a freelancer for our own startup.
تجربتي الشخصية في تعيين موظف حر في لشركتنا الناشئة الجديدة.
FYI, I've tweaked the context setting of this example,
لمعلوماتك، لقد قمت بتعديل إعدادات السياق لهذا المثال،
but the essence remains the same.
ولكن جوهر المثال لم يتغير.
We hired a developer who we paid to build a module on our tech platform,
وظفنا مطورًا ودفعنا له المال مقابل إنشاء نموذج نمطي لمنصتنا الإلكترونية،
which automatically would collect information about
والتي تتجمع عليها تلقائيًا معلومات خاصة
social impact organizations who are trying to help underprivileged communities.
بمنظمات التأثير الاجتماعي التي تحاول مساعدة المجتمعات الفقيرة.
Now, this module has an admin interface where
لهذا النموذج واجهة المسئول حيث
the employees of our startup can see the status of the activity performed by the module.
يستطيع موظفي شركتنا الناشئة الإطلاع على حالة النشاط الذي تقوم به النموذج.
Now, we wanted to make the external interface of this module to be well-polished.
أردنا أن نجعل الواجهة الخارجية للنموذج جذابة.
The developer we hired was really skilled at his job.
وكان المطور الذي تم تعيينه ماهرًا جدًا في عمله.
In fact, I have not seen any developer better skilled than him
في الحقيقة لم أقابل مطور حر ماهر مثله
amongst all the freelancers that we have hired at that early in their careers so far.
بين كل المطورين الذين يشقون طريقهم في المجال.
The developer did a good job building the module,
قام المطور بعمل ممتاز في إنشاء النموذج،
but also focused on things we did not necessarily want to pay attention to.
ولكنه ركز أيضًا على أشياء لم نكن بالضرورة نهتم بها.
Since the admin module will be used internally,
حيث أن نموذج تحكُّم المشرف مُعد للاستخدام الداخلي،
we did not want to make it as polished as the external facing module.
ولم نكن نهتم بجعل الواجهة الخارجية جذابة بقدر الواجهة الخارجية.
The developer insisted on making things look nice on
وأصر المطور على جعل النموذج يبدو جذابًا بالنسبة
the admin module as well and the way they should be uniform across the platform.
لنموذج تحكُّم المشرف وأهتم أيضًا بتوحيد ذلك على المنصة.
Theoretically, that's a good thing to do,
نظريًا كان هذا عمل رائع،
but that was not our priority and did not fit into our budget.
ولكن لم يكن هذا ضمن أولويتنا ولم يتناسب مع ميزانيتنا.
Our priority is what our users see.
أولويتنا كانت الواجهة التي يراها المستخدم.
Internally, we could do away with an okay-looking interface for an internal employees.
وبالنسبة للاستخدام الداخلي للموظفين لم نكن نهتم بجعل الواجهة بنفس القدر من الجاذبية.
After some time, we ended up discontinuing work with that developer,
بعد فترة انتهى الأمر إلى تقليص العمل مع هذا المطور،
one of the best developers that we have ever had for a simple reason,
برغم أنه أحد أفضل المطورين الذين عملنا معهم نتيجة لسبب واحد
that we did not feel aligned with that developer.
وهو أننا لم نشعر بأن المطور يفهمنا.
When the alignment is missing, my friends,
وعندما لا نسير معًا على نفس الخط وفي نفس الاتجاه،
every task becomes a challenge.
تصبح كل مهمة صعبة.
I'll reiterate the two main points that we discussed,
سأؤكد على نقطتين تحدثنا عنهم،
hear the client and sense what their priorities are.
استمع إلى العميل واستشعر أولوياته.